<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5.X BLM Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: October 26, 2019
General Info Openers Single Target Rotation Recovery and Reopeners AoE Rotation (3+ Targets) Movement and Uptime Spell Speed Thresholds Leveling Rotations Macros About Gear Appendix Misc. My IGN is Caro Kann, and I’m a BLM main (now SCH (AND NOW AST) :pepega:) and this is my guide for playing 5.X BLM. In this guide, I go over the basics of the BLM rotation and offer some potential optimizations.</description></item><item><title>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</guid><description>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition An advanced guide to the class Last Update: 11/09/2019 - E3S, E4S added. Additional information on Salted Earth added.
Hi! Emiin Vanih [Lamia] here. Myself and my companions have developed a compendium of information that will hopefully help you take your Dark Knight playstyle to a new level. While tanking is easy to learn, with the right know-how, you can excel at the role, and lead your group to victory.</description></item><item><title>An In-Depth Guide To Guns and Robots v5.5</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</guid><description>Job Overview Machinist is a fast-paced physical ranged job that excels at quick burst damage and has the added benefit of free movement. While the base rotation for this job is somewhat strict, Machinist excels in dumping burst into raid buffs with flexible use of its gauge system. This guide’s aim is to break down the job’s rotation into something easy to digest whilst providing good practices to follow for overall gameplay.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only. It will not address the general principles of healing as they apply to all healers. Those things are discussed in Zyrk’s Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing.</description></item><item><title>Becoming A Better Tank</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</guid><description>Becoming A Better Tank Version 1.0 Torael Valdis | Jenova (NA) | Torael_Valdis#8120
This guide is written with the intention to be hosted on The Balance Discord and should not be hosted elsewhere without consent of the owner.
Table of Contents Introduction
Mindset
Mitigation
Mitigating As The Off Tank Facilitating Party Uptime
Damage
Consistency and Adaptability</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5 AST BiS SETS https://bit.ly/astgearcalc
So we&amp;rsquo;re here, finally with a proper writeup.
Making BiS was expected to be very difficult this tier with AST&amp;rsquo;s new affinity for SpS&amp;hellip;but instead it actually was quite easy. Avoid Piety like the plague and there you go, there&amp;rsquo;s your BiS pieces.
Higher Piety sets also have the nice consolation of having a wealth of Crit (rather than the traditional disgusting amounts of Det) so it won&amp;rsquo;t even feel that bad to swap to lower damage for the sake of Piety.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dragoon Best-in-Slot Lists 5.55 Best-in-Slot Gearsets 2.50 GCD (Raid Chest) - http://bit.ly/drg250raid
2.50 GCD (Tome Chest) - https://bit.ly/drg250tome Slight downgrade if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to get the E12S chest.
2.46 GCD - http://bit.ly/drg246bis
5.55 Best-in-Slot, no Relic 2.50 GCD - https://etro.gg/gearset/7f0557b6-d86f-4d3a-8953-4db56bd23488
2.46 GCD - https://etro.gg/gearset/bc44395f-4ce1-47aa-b52a-7bcbcb90d152
Ultimates Best-in-Slot Discussion If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to do one of the level 70 Ultimate encounters, you should just sync down current gear. If you wear anything with an Item Level higher than 418 for UCoB or 470 for UWU, you will maximize the two stats on the gear.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Paladin Best in Slot Gear Priority and Pre-BiS Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on personal loot availability. Prioritizing item level over substats is encouraged while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What is the BiS for Ultimates? UCoB / UWU / TEA ? Sets are currently being gathered in one doc: http://bit.ly/WARultimateBIS
Many pieces of gear are BiS when synced down.
The &amp;lsquo;low&amp;rsquo; stat on the higher ilvl gear will reach the stat cap on the lower ilvl gear.
This outweighs the melds you lose in some cases, and in others it is few points of stats behind.
UCoB: ilvl 418 and above will have both stats capped UWU: ilvl 470 and above will have both stats capped TEA: No available ilvl cap yet, syncing gear will not cap all substats and will ignore melding slots.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dark Knight Best In Slot Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS sets will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on what gear is available to you. Prioritizing item level over substats is generally recommended while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Best in Slot 5.58 Best in Slot (BiS) Compendium: *Damage is within negligible variance. Choose the set that best suits your comfort level. Fight specific recommendations to come at a later date.
Savage Relic BiS 5.58 Relic i530 BiS 2.41 - 13,892.9 DPS 2.43 - 13,850.0 DPS Non-Relic BiS Food: Chicken Fettuccine
i530 2.41 - 13,808.7 DPS
Level 70 Ultimates Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB) BiS UCoB i515 Relic BiS The Weapon&amp;rsquo;s Refrain (UWU) BiS UWU i515 Relic BiS Level 80 Ultimates 5.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</guid><description>Saving The Dragoon Overview Dragoon is a very static melee dps Job. You have strict, long combos to execute and timers within those combos that need to be maintained. Unlike other Jobs - especially other melee - which rely upon a priority system for their basic GCD rotation, Dragoon instead has static buttons to press in a specific order with very little variance. Shadowbringers brings with it a new reliance on hitting proper positionals to trigger new skills.</description></item><item><title>Expert: The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Table of Contents [Table of Contents]
[Introduction]
[The 5.0 Samurai Rotation Changes]
Tsubame Gaeshi is Restrictive and Inflexible [The Crumbs: Normalised Cooldown Times] [The Solution: A Rotation Loop] [Optimising Potency]
[Maximising Yukikaze Combo Usage] [Maintaining GCD Count]</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</guid><description>Paladin FAQ Why is Circle of Scorn used immediately in the opener?
Circle of Scorn is used before Fight or Flight in most openers and kept on cooldown in most phases for two reasons:
Its short cooldown (25 seconds) is equal to the duration of Fight or Flight, meaning one CoS usage should always occur during FoF regardless of their respective timings, given full uptime. Its high DoT uptime (~60%) means that any delays are likely to cost ticks at the end of the phase, resulting in a potency loss overall.</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</guid><description>Introduction to Gunbreaker
Author Skills and Abilities
Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Offensive Off Global Cooldown Abilities Defensive Off Global Cool Down Abilities Utility Off Global Cool Down Abilities Combos
What Does/Doesn’t Break Combos AoE or Single Target No Mercy Windows Bloodfest Cartridge Usage Openers
Rotation
Priority System GCD Uptime Stat Priorities</description></item><item><title>How to Fell Cleave - An Angry Wannabe-Healer, also known as Warrior 5.0 - The Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/how-to-fell-cleave-an-angry-wannabe-healer-also-known-as-warrior-5-0-the-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/how-to-fell-cleave-an-angry-wannabe-healer-also-known-as-warrior-5-0-the-guide/</guid><description>How to Fell Cleave &amp;ldquo;An Angry Wannabe-Healer Guide&amp;rdquo; Warrior Primer v5.3 (last update 2021-08-14)
A comprehensive guide on Warrior’s gameplay, current info and theory Introduction
Job Overview
tl;dr
Abilities Preview
Single Target Area of Effect oGCD Utility The Beast Gauge Abilities In-Depth Overview
Single Target Area of Effect oGCD Utility The Openers and Rotation</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Dark Knight</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 Introduction
Skills and Abilities Overview
Tank Stance
Single Target GCDs
Abilities (oGCDs)
Buffs Offensive Defensive or Utility AoE
Other Actions (Infrequently Used)
Opener
Rotation
Using Blood Weapon and Delirium Pooling Resources for Raid Buffs Helpful Macros</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Paladin Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</guid><description>the useless pre-Endwalker guide update by nikroulah#1605
Skills and Abilities Overview Buffs Iron Will
Toggle • 10s cooldown after toggling on • no cooldown for toggling off
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.)
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank)
Fight or Flight
60s cooldown
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds</description></item><item><title>Leveling Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker-levelling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker-levelling-guide/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Levelling Rotations Levels 15-29 (Solid Barrel at 26+)
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Single target: (15-29) Keen Edge + Brutal Shell | (26-29) Solid Barrel ST combo
2 or more targets: Demon Slice spam
Levels 30-39 &amp;gt; Single target: Burst Strike &amp;gt; Solid Barrel ST combo
3 or more targets: Demon Slice spam
Levels 40-59 (Sonic Break at 54+)
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Single target: Sonic Break &amp;gt; Burst Strike &amp;gt; Solid Barrel ST combo</description></item><item><title>Monk FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</guid><description>Is Double True Strike dead?
As purely the best option, yup, go back to 1:1 Twin Snakes and True.
What&amp;rsquo;s with the double Dragon Kick in the openers?
With Standard, you DK after Perfect Balance for DK&amp;rsquo;s higher potency and again later to gain Leaden finally. With Early Buff a stanceless Leaden Boot after PB is worse on average than using the DK to guarantee a crit one.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Ninja
What is Ninja?
Skills and Abilities
Weaponskills (Commonly referred to as GCDs) Ninjutsus/Mudras Regular Abilities(oGCDs) Ninki Utility Abilities Traits Rotation
Base Combo Ninki Usage Ninjutsu Usage oGCD Usage Trick Attack Rotation Ten Chi Jin (TCJ) Usage Multi-Target Rotation Best-In-Slot (BiS)
Optimization
Optimizing Around Kill Times Optimizing Around Downtime Niche Optimizations Thanks</description></item><item><title>Opener and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/opener-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/opener-and-rotation/</guid><description>Paladin Opener and Rotation Tanks currently use Grade 4 Tinctures of Strength (Strength also affects tank magic potency, including healing)
Quick Opener/Rotation Graphic: Alternative In-Depth Graphic: 60 Second Rotation Paladin&amp;rsquo;s natural rotation is approximately 63 seconds long, which means Fight or Flight and Requiescat (both with 60-second cooldowns) are delayed by 1 GCD per minute. In some situations this can cost FoF GCDs or even a Confiteor usage before the end of a phase, and in long encounters with minimal downtime, physical oGCDs must eventually be delayed as well to stay lined up with FoF.</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Openers Listed below are all current openers and the reasoning as to why each one should be selected. It is very important that you attempt to put as much damage into the raid buffs of your party as possible. Wildfire is not flexible at all, as it is on a strict two minute timer, and because of this, it should be placed properly in the opener based on your party composition.</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Dark Knight Openers and Rotation Openers DRK has a several different options for openers, not all of which are listed here. Fight timings and party composition can both affect which opener is best, based on when you can keep uptime on the boss and when raid buffs are used. Fight-specific opener information can be found in #drk_encounter and #drk_questions (often in the pins). This section will list some General-purpose DRK openers which work relatively well in most situations.</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotation</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers-and-rotation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers-and-rotation/</guid><description>Warrior Openers and Rotation Opener Optimization At present, there is only a single worthy opener for Warriors, mainly because we want to get Inner Release on cooldown as soon as possible to maximize its usage, and because we can fit an extra Fell Cleave inside the potion by abusing Inner Release’s +15s Eye extension mechanics.
IC IR IC IC Opener IC IR IC IC opener takes advantage of the potion’s whole duration, landing in three Inner Chaos, two combo finishers, a Fell Cleave and all the important oGCDs.</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotations</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers-and-rotations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers-and-rotations/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Openers and Rotations Openers Openers are designed to do a few very important things:
Get abilities on cooldown as soon as possible. This keeps us from sitting on skills that are ready which could potentially cause lost usages. Get strong abilities under raid buffs. This helps to maximize damage done. More damage is always better, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s free! Set up our rotation for the rest of the fight (or until a transition/extended period of downtime).</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: Eden's Promise</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/edens-promise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/edens-promise/</guid><description>Table of Contents E9S E10S E11S E12S: Door Boss E12S: Oracle of Darkness E9S Movement for Brambles into Anti-Air/Wide-Angle In the first minute of the fight, it is preferred to hold your Swiftcast. This allows your Dualcast window to align better for later mechanics, such as for placing your bramble and tethers. What you need to use for the tether movement may vary based on the Brambles strategy your group does, but generally, a single Dualcast will likely be enough, adding Sprint if necessary.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: The Epic of Alexander (TEA)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-epic-of-alexander-tea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-epic-of-alexander-tea/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Living Liquid Phase 2: Brute Justice and Cruise Chaser Phase 3: Alexander Prime Phase 4: Perfect Alexander Clear PoVs Clear Logs General Fight Tips Managing Resources For all phases in TEA you should aim to finish capped with, or very close to 100 | 100 Black and White mana. One of RDM’s greatest strengths is the ability to pool resources for use in later parts of the fight, and ending the phase capped on mana allows you to execute a strong reopener in the next phase with two melee combos under raid buffs thanks to Manafication.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: The Weapon's Refrain (UWU)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-weapons-refrain-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-weapons-refrain-ultimate/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Garuda Phase 2: Ifrit Phase 3: Titan Phase 4: Ultima Weapon Clear PoVs Clear Logs General Fight Tips Managing Resources Due to damage scaling in Shadowbringers, push timings in The Weapon’s Refrain can vary greatly, between groups and even between pulls in the same group. Therefore, you should use this guide for a general idea of how to manage each phase, but keep in mind this may not always work for you, and you should aim to find a timeline that works for you during progression.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ucob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ucob/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Twintania Phase 2: Nael Van Darnus Phase 3: Bahamut Prime Phase 4: Adds Phase Phase 5: Golden Bahamut Clear PoVs Clear Logs General Fight Tips Manafication Manafication is changed in Shadowbringers by a trait at Lv.74 which means that in Lv.70 content it functions the same way it did in Stormblood: with no damage buff and a 120s cooldown.</description></item><item><title>RDM Skill Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skill-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skill-overview/</guid><description>Red Mage Skill Overview All skills are listed with their level 80 effects and potencies. Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Jolt II A 290 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases both Black and White Mana by 3. Verthunder A 370 potency Spell with a cast time of five seconds that increases Black Mana by 11.</description></item><item><title>Reaper: What We Know So Far</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</guid><description>Reaper will be a new job coming to Final Fantasy XIV in the Endwalker expansion. As of September of 2021, we only know a few things about Reaper, and as we learn more we will update this page.
Gameplay Here are the following gameplay mechanics we know about Reaper:
It will be a melee DPS They will wield a Scythe as its main weapon and will use the &amp;ldquo;Maiming&amp;rdquo; armor, similar to DRG.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/red-mage-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/red-mage-guide/</guid><description>Overview
Major Changes and Additions in 5.x
Role Actions Enchanted Reprise Scorch Acceleration Engagement Impact AoE rotation Balancing your Mana
Red Mage Damage Types
Red Mage Cheat Sheet (TL;DR)
Damage oGCD Usage
Enchanted Reprise Manafication Usage
Managing your procs
Swiftcast Usage
Efficiently fishing for procs when below 80|80</description></item><item><title>Sage: What We Know So Far</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/sage/sage-what-we-know-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/sage/sage-what-we-know-so-far/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The nation of Sharlayan is the cradle of knowledge, and the Studium its foremost institution of learning. Yet more so than its incomparable library and formidable assemblage of Archons, this prestigious academy is famed for blending traditionally distinct fields to produce revolutionary new disciplines. Among these, perhaps the most distinguished is an altruistic art which draws upon the wisdom of aetherology, sorcery, and medicine. Dubbed somanoutics, the art seeks to heal and protect by manipulating corporeal aether through the use of nouliths, a flying array of foci.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</guid><description>Indomitable, A Thourough Guide to Scholar
Author Acknowledgements
What Does Scholar Do?
Actions
DPS GCDs DPS oGCDs Healing GCDs Healing oGCDs Utility Spells/Abilities Fairy Abillities Other Abilities Role Actions All About DPS
Opener How DoT&amp;rsquo;s Work The GCD and Weaving
How the Fairy Works
Problems With The Fairy Opportunity Costs</description></item><item><title>Skill Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skill-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skill-overview/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Skills Overview Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Keen Edge The first skill of our basic combo. 200 potency. Brutal Shell The second skill of our basic combo. 300 potency when used after Keen Edge. Heals for 200 potency and gives a shield equal to the amount healed. Solid Barrel The final skill of our basic combo.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</guid><description>DPS GCDs Broil III
This is your predominant spell that you will cast most often during any given encounter. This is your filler DPS spell that you cast when your DoT is already ticking and nothing else needs to be done.
Art Of War
This is the spell for AOE DPS. It has a base potency of 160. This is better than Broil III if there are two or more targets.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</guid><description>Dark Knight Skills and Abilities Overview Tank Stance Grit
Toggle - Ten second cooldown after toggling on • No cooldown for toggling off Multiplies enmity (aggro, hate, etc) generation by ten Keep this on in dungeons or as the current maintank (in content with more than one tank) Single Target GCDs Souleater Combo
200 &amp;gt; 300 &amp;gt; 400 potency
Hard Slash Syphon Strike: +600 MP Souleater: +20 Blood, 300p heal Bloodspiller</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</guid><description>Paladin Skills Overview Buffs Iron Will
Toggle • 10s cooldown after toggling on • No cooldown for toggling off
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.)
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank)
Fight or Flight
60s cooldown
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds
By using Fight or Flight late into the GCD (just before the next GCD), it is possible to fit 11 physical GCDs into the buff window.</description></item><item><title>Skills Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</guid><description>Warrior Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Heavy Swing Standard basic attack to initiate both the Storm’s Eye Combo and the Storm’s Path Combo, consisting of Heavy Swing, Maim, Storm’s Eye and Heavy Swing, Maim, Storm’s Path respectively. 200 potency GCD Maim 320 potency if combo’d after Heavy Swing.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Astrologian Stats and Materia What should I meld? Outside of Best in Slot, your meld priority should be;
Piety to comfort (if needed) Sps if you want to hit a certain GCD tier Crit Det/dh Sps. That said, the difference between meld setups is so small overall that you could opt for Det over Crit, or take more Spell Speed than usual if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re more comfortable with during prog.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Stat Priority Item Level
Affects Strength and Weapon Damage (for weapons) Significantly affects all damage dealt Prioritize over substat type Critical Hit
Priority meld on all gear (unless already capped on that piece) Skill Speed
Meld only to reach preferred GCD speed (enough to consistently get 5 GCDs in Blood Weapon) #bot_spam !xivmath rspeed 2.43 or see the tiers below Direct Hit Rate</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority-and-materia/</guid><description>Meld Priority Gunbreaker meld priority is fairly simple:
Item Level
Higher item level means higher stats, and is usually an upgrade regardless of stat types. RARE EXCEPTIONS EXIST! Critical Hit
Meld to each item&amp;rsquo;s substat cap, unless it&amp;rsquo;s red or naturally capped. Exceptions of +59 instead of +60 exist Skill Speed
Gunbreaker is very versatile and can be played at a lot of GCD tiers.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Paladin Stats and Materia Note: This priority is also applicable to customizable (&amp;ldquo;relic&amp;rdquo;) Augmented Law&amp;rsquo;s Order weapons (515) and Blade&amp;rsquo;s weapons (535) for current content, before best-in-slot is obtained, excluding direct hit rate (which cannot be added to these weapons). Use the Tank Gear Manager to make educated gearing and melding decisions with precise stat tiering in mind.
Physical Damage (weapon only)
Significantly affects all damage dealt Always proportional to item level Cannot be melded Strength</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Warrior Stats and Materia With access to the information we know now, utilizing community tools such as the current Tank DPS calculator allows us to more accurately determine what gear and melds should be used.
For Stat Tiers, refer to TheoryJerks/AkhMorning’s website.
Melding priority Crit &amp;gt; Comfy SkS &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt; Ten
Direct Hit is avoided altogether because of how Inner Chaos and Inner Release work: Direct Hit has no effect in either of those.</description></item><item><title>Tanking FAQ</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/tanking-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/tanking-faq/</guid><description>Tanking FAQ What Food / Potion do tanks use? Grade 4 Tincture of Strength Chicken Fettuccine OR Smoked Chicken What do I meld? Read the &amp;ldquo;Stats&amp;rdquo; section
Why is my combo breaking? The combo timer is exactly 15 seconds long. This means that you can do the following:
Combo 1 Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Combo 2 As long as the time between the cast of Combo 1 and Combo 2 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exceed 15s.</description></item><item><title>Tanking Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Tanking Stats and Materia Stats Stat Priority Weapon Damage Main stat (Str/Vit on tanks) Substats There are no &amp;ldquo;Stat weights&amp;rdquo;.
Weapon Damage almost always comes with main stat increase.
Higher item level almost always comes with main stat increase.
Upgrade your gear as often as possible
Skill Speed (at level 80) 2.43s GCD - 1015 SkS 2.42s GCD - 1117 SkS 2.</description></item><item><title>The Correct Way to Kick an Eldritch Horror in the Jaw</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/monk/mnk-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/monk/mnk-guide/</guid><description>A Monk Guide by Perfect Balance Introduction Hello and welcome to Monkey, I am Perfect Balance and I am going to feed you the information you need to punch and kick at a decent level in the patch of our lord and saviour 5.58. You can get in touch with me on discord at wulf#8419, or on Twitter. at @RiddleOfFire. I&amp;rsquo;m not one for lengthy introductions, so let&amp;rsquo;s get to feeding.</description></item><item><title>The Pursuit of Comfiness - Bard Guide 5.X</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/bard/the-pursuit-of-comfiness-bard-guide-5-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/bard/the-pursuit-of-comfiness-bard-guide-5-x/</guid><description>The Pursuit of Comfiness - Bard Guide 5.X Authors by Verzell Varion [Adamantoise] with contributions from Im’hotep Rah [Goblin], Sana Cetonis [Sargatanas], Ellunavi Sevald [Sargatanas], Yumiya Nagatsuki [Behemoth], Elya Kura [Ragnarok]
Foreword Hi all! Welcome to our Bard guide, freshly revamped for the 5.x Shadowbringers expansion. This guide will cover concepts of Bard gameplay, from the very fundamentals to the limits of optimization, as well as serving as a pocket reference for all aspects of Bard.</description></item><item><title>Ultimate - The Epic of Alexander</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/ultimate-the-epic-of-alexander/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/ultimate-the-epic-of-alexander/</guid><description>Warrior TEA Tips and Tricks Living Liquid Phase Rampart seven seconds to prepull to have it last for the first cleave, and to be up for the tank tether later. If you facepull and do Inner Chaos, Inner Release, Inner Chaos, you can get the last cleave off in IR before dodging out for the second Protean. Shake It Off after you put Storm&amp;rsquo;s Eye up to have it back up for second Protean.</description></item><item><title>Ultimate Raids</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/ultimate-raids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/ultimate-raids/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Ultimates Table of Contents A Note Regarding Ultimates
Level 70 Ultimates
The Unending Coils of Bahamut The Weapon&amp;rsquo;s Refrain Openers Best in Slot Points of View Level 80 Ultimates
The Epic of Alexander Opener Best in Slot Points of View FAQ
A Note Regarding Ultimates: Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s mitigation plans will vary significantly depending on how fast your group pushes each phase.</description></item><item><title>Zyrk's Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</guid><description>Zyrk’s FFXIV Shadowbringers Healing Guide Learn how to hate your party, the game, and yourself About the Author Hi, I’m Zyrkhan Dar’locke. My name is blue on The Balance, and that’s basically all I have to say for myself. You may also know me as “what?” and “literally who.” I’m here to talk about healing and stuff, because I guess I like it or something, mostly because I don’t respect myself.</description></item></channel></rss>