<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5.X BLM Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: October 26, 2019
General Info Openers Single Target Rotation Recovery and Reopeners AoE Rotation (3+ Targets) Movement and Uptime Spell Speed Thresholds Leveling Rotations Macros About Gear Appendix Misc. My IGN is Caro Kann, and I’m a BLM main (now SCH (AND NOW AST) :pepega:) and this is my guide for playing 5.X BLM. In this guide, I go over the basics of the BLM rotation and offer some potential optimizations.</description></item><item><title>An In-Depth Guide To Guns and Robots v5.5</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</guid><description>Job Overview Machinist is a fast-paced physical ranged job that excels at quick burst damage and has the added benefit of free movement. While the base rotation for this job is somewhat strict, Machinist excels in dumping burst into raid buffs with flexible use of its gauge system. This guide’s aim is to break down the job’s rotation into something easy to digest whilst providing good practices to follow for overall gameplay.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
This guide now has a web hosted version here. The site is in development, so there may be hiccups. The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</guid><description>Saving The Dragoon Overview Dragoon is a very static melee dps Job. You have strict, long combos to execute and timers within those combos that need to be maintained. Unlike other Jobs - especially other melee - which rely upon a priority system for their basic GCD rotation, Dragoon instead has static buttons to press in a specific order with very little variance. Shadowbringers brings with it a new reliance on hitting proper positionals to trigger new skills.</description></item><item><title>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide (sry i need to put this somewhere lol)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide-sry-i-need-to-put-this-somewhere-lol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide-sry-i-need-to-put-this-somewhere-lol/</guid><description>Introduction This is a comprehensive guide aimed towards players entering endgame – Level 90 – for the first time and getting overwhelmed with FFXIV&amp;rsquo;s gear progression systems. This guide will help you get an understanding of how FFXIV’s endgame systems work, as well as how to gear up and what types of endgame PvE content exist.
Step 1. Finish MSQ, get AF Gear, and farm Tomestones for gear
Explanation of Terms, Loot, and Lockouts Lockout Reset All weekly lockouts are reset at Tuesday, 1AM PST/4 AM EST/8AM GMT.</description></item><item><title>Expert: The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Table of Contents Table of Contents
Introduction
The 5.0 Samurai Rotation Changes
Tsubame Gaeshi is Restrictive and Inflexible [The Crumbs: Normalised Cooldown Times] [The Solution: A Rotation Loop] [Optimising Potency]
[Maximising Yukikaze Combo Usage] [Maintaining GCD Count]</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</guid><description>Introduction to Gunbreaker
Author Skills and Abilities
Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Offensive Off Global Cooldown Abilities Defensive Off Global Cool Down Abilities Utility Off Global Cool Down Abilities Combos
What Does/Doesn’t Break Combos AoE or Single Target No Mercy Windows Bloodfest Cartridge Usage Openers
Rotation
Priority System GCD Uptime Stat Priorities</description></item><item><title>Ninja Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Ninja
What is Ninja?
Skills and Abilities
Weaponskills (Commonly referred to as GCDs) Ninjutsus/Mudras Regular Abilities(oGCDs) Ninki Utility Abilities Traits Rotation
Base Combo Ninki Usage Ninjutsu Usage oGCD Usage Trick Attack Rotation Ten Chi Jin (TCJ) Usage Multi-Target Rotation Best-In-Slot (BiS)
Optimization
Optimizing Around Kill Times Optimizing Around Downtime Niche Optimizations Thanks</description></item><item><title>Reaper - What we know so far</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</guid><description>As we prepare for Endwalker, the Balance Team is keeping a close eye on anything Reaper related. Currently we only have the job introduction trailer and below will be some an analysis of this video. I wanted to spend sometime addressing where the biggest source of our information will come from, pre launch &amp;ndash; The media tour.
For Shadowbringers the media tour was a pretty huge success, not only for media content creators but also for guide writers and theorycrafters.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</guid><description>Indomitable, A Thorough Guide to Scholar
Author Acknowledgements
What Does Scholar Do?
Actions
DPS GCDs DPS oGCDs Healing GCDs Healing oGCDs Utility Spells/Abilities Fairy Abilities Other Abilities Role Actions All About DPS
Opener How DoT&amp;rsquo;s Work The GCD and Weaving
How the Fairy Works
Problems With The Fairy Opportunity Costs</description></item><item><title>Zyrk's Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</guid><description>Zyrk’s FFXIV Shadowbringers Healing Guide Learn how to hate your party, the game, and yourself About the Author Hi, I’m Zyrkhan Dar’locke. My name is blue on The Balance, and that’s basically all I have to say for myself. You may also know me as “what?” and “literally who.” I’m here to talk about healing and stuff, because I guess I like it or something, mostly because I don’t respect myself.</description></item></channel></rss>