<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jobs on Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/</link><description>Recent content in Jobs on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5.X BLM Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/5-x-blm-guide/</guid><description>Last updated: October 26, 2019
General Info Openers Single Target Rotation Recovery and Reopeners AoE Rotation (3+ Targets) Movement and Uptime Spell Speed Thresholds Leveling Rotations Macros About Gear Appendix Misc. My IGN is Caro Kann, and I’m a BLM main (now SCH (AND NOW AST) :pepega:) and this is my guide for playing 5.X BLM. In this guide, I go over the basics of the BLM rotation and offer some potential optimizations.</description></item><item><title>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/an-in-depth-look-at-dark-knight-shadowbringers-edition/</guid><description>An In Depth look at Dark Knight - Shadowbringers Edition An advanced guide to the class Last Update: 11/09/2019 - E3S, E4S added. Additional information on Salted Earth added.
Hi! Emiin Vanih [Lamia] here. Myself and my companions have developed a compendium of information that will hopefully help you take your Dark Knight playstyle to a new level. While tanking is easy to learn, with the right know-how, you can excel at the role, and lead your group to victory.</description></item><item><title>An In-Depth Guide To Guns and Robots v5.5</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-mch-stuff/</guid><description>Job Overview Machinist is a fast-paced physical ranged job that excels at quick burst damage and has the added benefit of free movement. While the base rotation for this job is somewhat strict, Machinist excels in dumping burst into raid buffs with flexible use of its gauge system. This guide’s aim is to break down the job’s rotation into something easy to digest whilst providing good practices to follow for overall gameplay.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/astrologian-guide/</guid><description>Intro to Astrologian Who Needs MP When You’re This Pretty? Brought to you by Zyrkhan Dar’locke, AKA Literally Who
No, we still can’t be Gambit
The Scope of this Guide As the title implies, this guide is intended to function as an introduction to Astrologian. This guide is concerned with Astrologian only. It will not address the general principles of healing as they apply to all healers. Those things are discussed in Zyrk’s Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing.</description></item><item><title>Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Best in Slot 5.58 Best in Slot (BiS) Compendium: *Damage is within negligible variance. Choose the set that best suits your comfort level. Fight specific recommendations to come at a later date.
Savage Relic BiS 5.58 Relic i530 BiS 2.41 - 13,892.9 DPS 2.43 - 13,850.0 DPS Non-Relic BiS Food: Chicken Fettuccine
i530 2.41 - 13,808.7 DPS
Level 70 Ultimates Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB) BiS UCoB i515 Relic BiS The Weapon&amp;rsquo;s Refrain (UWU) BiS UWU i515 Relic BiS Level 80 Ultimates 5.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/saving-the-dragoon/</guid><description>Saving The Dragoon Overview Dragoon is a very static melee dps Job. You have strict, long combos to execute and timers within those combos that need to be maintained. Unlike other Jobs - especially other melee - which rely upon a priority system for their basic GCD rotation, Dragoon instead has static buttons to press in a specific order with very little variance. Shadowbringers brings with it a new reliance on hitting proper positionals to trigger new skills.</description></item><item><title>Expert: The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/samurai/expert-the-shadowbringers-samurai-compendium/</guid><description>The Shadowbringers Samurai Compendium An Exploration of 5.0 Samurai Mechanics By Jahaudant @ The Balance &amp;amp; DPS Tools Discords Last Updated 17th April 2020
Table of Contents [Table of Contents]
[Introduction]
[The 5.0 Samurai Rotation Changes]
Tsubame Gaeshi is Restrictive and Inflexible [The Crumbs: Normalised Cooldown Times] [The Solution: A Rotation Loop] [Optimising Potency]
[Maximising Yukikaze Combo Usage] [Maintaining GCD Count]</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker/</guid><description>Introduction to Gunbreaker
Author Skills and Abilities
Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Offensive Off Global Cooldown Abilities Defensive Off Global Cool Down Abilities Utility Off Global Cool Down Abilities Combos
What Does/Doesn’t Break Combos AoE or Single Target No Mercy Windows Bloodfest Cartridge Usage Openers
Rotation
Priority System GCD Uptime Stat Priorities</description></item><item><title>How to Fell Cleave - An Angry Wannabe-Healer, also known as Warrior 5.0 - The Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/how-to-fell-cleave-an-angry-wannabe-healer-also-known-as-warrior-5-0-the-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/how-to-fell-cleave-an-angry-wannabe-healer-also-known-as-warrior-5-0-the-guide/</guid><description>How to Fell Cleave &amp;ldquo;An Angry Wannabe-Healer Guide&amp;rdquo; Warrior Primer v5.3 (last update 2021-08-14)
A comprehensive guide on Warrior’s gameplay, current info and theory Introduction
Job Overview
tl;dr
Abilities Preview
Single Target Area of Effect oGCD Utility The Beast Gauge Abilities In-Depth Overview
Single Target Area of Effect oGCD Utility The Openers and Rotation</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Dark Knight</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/introduction-to-dark-knight/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 Introduction
Skills and Abilities Overview
Tank Stance
Single Target GCDs
Abilities (oGCDs)
Buffs Offensive Defensive or Utility AoE
Other Actions (Infrequently Used)
Opener
Rotation
Using Blood Weapon and Delirium Pooling Resources for Raid Buffs Helpful Macros</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Paladin Shadowbringers Edition</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/introduction-to-paladin-in-shadowbringers/</guid><description>the useless pre-Endwalker guide update by nikroulah#1605
Skills and Abilities Overview Buffs Iron WillToggle • 10s cooldown after toggling on • no cooldown for toggling off
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.)
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank)
Fight or Flight60s cooldown
+25% physical damage for 25 seconds
By using Fight or Flight late into the GCD (just before the next GCD), it is possible to fit 11 physical GCDs into the buff window.</description></item><item><title>Leveling Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker-levelling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/gunbreaker-levelling-guide/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Levelling Rotations Levels 15-29 (Solid Barrel at 26+)
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Single target: (15-29) Keen Edge + Brutal Shell | (26-29) Solid Barrel ST combo
2 or more targets: Demon Slice spam
Levels 30-39 &amp;gt; Single target: Burst Strike &amp;gt; Solid Barrel ST combo
3 or more targets: Demon Slice spam
Levels 40-59 (Sonic Break at 54+)
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Single target: Sonic Break &amp;gt; Burst Strike &amp;gt; Solid Barrel ST combo</description></item><item><title>Ninja Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/ninja/ninja-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Ninja
What is Ninja?
Skills and Abilities
Weaponskills (Commonly referred to as GCDs) Ninjutsus/Mudras Regular Abilities(oGCDs) Ninki Utility Abilities Traits Rotation
Base Combo Ninki Usage Ninjutsu Usage oGCD Usage Trick Attack Rotation Ten Chi Jin (TCJ) Usage Multi-Target Rotation Best-In-Slot (BiS)
Optimization
Optimizing Around Kill Times Optimizing Around Downtime Niche Optimizations Thanks</description></item><item><title>Openers and Rotations</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers-and-rotations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers-and-rotations/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Openers and Rotations Openers Openers are designed to do a few very important things:
Get abilities on cooldown as soon as possible. This keeps us from sitting on skills that are ready which could potentially cause lost usages. Get strong abilities under raid buffs. This helps to maximize damage done. More damage is always better, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s free! Set up our rotation for the rest of the fight (or until a transition/extended period of downtime).</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: Eden's Promise</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/edens-promise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/edens-promise/</guid><description>Table of Contents E9S E10S E11S E12S: Door Boss E12S: Oracle of Darkness E9S Movement for Brambles into Anti-Air/Wide-Angle In the first minute of the fight, it is preferred to hold your Swiftcast. This allows your Dualcast window to align better for later mechanics, such as for placing your bramble and tethers. What you need to use for the tether movement may vary based on the Brambles strategy your group does, but generally, a single Dualcast will likely be enough, adding Sprint if necessary.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: The Epic of Alexander (TEA)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-epic-of-alexander-tea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-epic-of-alexander-tea/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Living Liquid Phase 2: Brute Justice and Cruise Chaser Phase 3: Alexander Prime Phase 4: Perfect Alexander Clear PoVs Clear Logs Credits Written in bulk by Lana White, with additional information, checking &amp;amp; theorycrafting from Hinoka Shirasagi, Laille Ormesaing, and Velox Vulpes.
General Fight Tips Managing Resources For all phases in TEA you should aim to finish capped with, or very close to 100 | 100 Black and White mana.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: The Weapon's Refrain (UWU)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-weapons-refrain-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-the-weapons-refrain-ultimate/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Garuda Phase 2: Ifrit Phase 3: Titan Phase 4: Ultima Weapon Clear PoVs Clear Logs Credits Written in bulk by Laille Ormesaing, with thanks to Lana White and Verdandi Schwartz for co-writing and editing, as well as Meru Lucis for graphical contributions and editing. With additional information, checking and theorycrafting from Argen Yin, Hinoka Shirasagi and Mazz Maryoku.</description></item><item><title>RDM Fight Tips: Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ucob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/rdm-fight-tips-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ucob/</guid><description>Table of Contents Credits General Fight Tips Phase 1: Twintania Phase 2: Nael Van Darnus Phase 3: Bahamut Prime Phase 4: Adds Phase Phase 5: Golden Bahamut Clear PoVs Clear Logs Credits Written in bulk by Lana White with additional information, checking &amp;amp; theorycrafting from Phoebe No’Saa, Hinoka Shirasagi and Laille Ormesaing.
General Fight Tips Manafication Manafication is changed in Shadowbringers by a trait at Lv.</description></item><item><title>Reaper - What we know so far</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/melee/reaper/reaper-what-we-know-so-far/</guid><description>As we prepare for Endwalker, the Balance Team is keeping a close eye on anything Reaper related. Currently we only have the job introduction trailer and below will be some an analysis of this video. I wanted to spend sometime addressing where the biggest source of our information will come from, pre launch &amp;ndash; The media tour.
For Shadowbringers the media tour was a pretty huge success, not only for media content creators but also for guide writers and theorycrafters.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/red-mage-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/red-mage-guide/</guid><description>Overview
Major Changes and Additions in 5.x
Role Actions Enchanted Reprise Scorch Acceleration Engagement Impact AoE rotation Balancing your Mana
Red Mage Damage Types
Red Mage Cheat Sheet (TL;DR)
Damage oGCD Usage
Enchanted Reprise Manafication Usage
Managing your procs
Swiftcast Usage
Efficiently fishing for procs when below 80|80</description></item><item><title>Scholar Guide</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/healers/scholar/scholar-guide/</guid><description>Indomitable, A Thorough Guide to Scholar
Author Acknowledgements
What Does Scholar Do?
Actions
DPS GCDs DPS oGCDs Healing GCDs Healing oGCDs Utility Spells/Abilities Fairy Abilities Other Abilities Role Actions All About DPS
Opener How DoT&amp;rsquo;s Work The GCD and Weaving
How the Fairy Works
Problems With The Fairy Opportunity Costs</description></item><item><title>Skill Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skill-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skill-overview/</guid><description>Red Mage Skills Overview All skills are listed with their level 80 effects and potencies. Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Jolt II A 290 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases both Black and White Mana by 3. Verthunder A 370 potency Spell with a cast time of five seconds that increases Black Mana by 11.</description></item><item><title>Skill Overview</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skill-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skill-overview/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Skills Overview Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Keen Edge The first skill of our basic combo. 200 potency. Brutal Shell The second skill of our basic combo. 300 potency when used after Keen Edge. Heals for 200 potency and gives a shield equal to the amount healed. Solid Barrel The final skill of our basic combo.</description></item><item><title>Stats and Materia</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority-and-materia/</guid><description>Meld Priority Gunbreaker meld priority is fairly simple:
Item Level
Higher item level means higher stats, and is usually an upgrade regardless of stat types. RARE EXCEPTIONS EXIST! Critical Hit
Meld to each item&amp;rsquo;s substat cap, unless it&amp;rsquo;s red or naturally capped. Exceptions of +59 instead of +60 exist Skill Speed
Gunbreaker is very versatile and can be played at a lot of GCD tiers.</description></item><item><title>The Pursuit of Comfiness - Bard Guide 5.X</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/bard/the-pursuit-of-comfiness-bard-guide-5-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/ranged/bard/the-pursuit-of-comfiness-bard-guide-5-x/</guid><description>The Pursuit of Comfiness - Bard Guide 5.X Authors by Verzell Varion [Adamantoise] with contributions from Im’hotep Rah [Goblin], Sana Cetonis [Sargatanas], Ellunavi Sevald [Sargatanas], Yumiya Nagatsuki [Behemoth], Elya Kura [Ragnarok]
Foreword Hi all! Welcome to our Bard guide, freshly revamped for the 5.x Shadowbringers expansion. This guide will cover concepts of Bard gameplay, from the very fundamentals to the limits of optimization, as well as serving as a pocket reference for all aspects of Bard.</description></item><item><title>Ultimate Raids</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/ultimate-raids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/ultimate-raids/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Ultimates Table of Contents A Note Regarding Ultimates
Level 70 Ultimates
The Unending Coils of Bahamut The Weapon&amp;rsquo;s Refrain Openers Best in Slot Points of View Level 80 Ultimates
The Epic of Alexander Opener Best in Slot Points of View FAQ
A Note Regarding Ultimates: Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s mitigation plans will vary significantly depending on how fast your group pushes each phase.</description></item></channel></rss>