<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guides on Balance Guides</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Becoming A Better Tank</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</guid><description>Becoming A Better Tank Version 1.0 Torael Valdis | Jenova (NA) | Torael_Valdis#8120
This guide is written with the intention to be hosted on The Balance Discord and should not be hosted elsewhere without consent of the owner.
Table of Contents Introduction
Mindset
Mitigation
Mitigating As The Off Tank Facilitating Party Uptime
Damage
Consistency and Adaptability</description></item><item><title>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide (sry i need to put this somewhere lol)</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide-sry-i-need-to-put-this-somewhere-lol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide-sry-i-need-to-put-this-somewhere-lol/</guid><description>Introduction This is a comprehensive guide aimed towards players entering endgame – Level 90 – for the first time and getting overwhelmed with FFXIV&amp;rsquo;s gear progression systems. This guide will help you get an understanding of how FFXIV’s endgame systems work, as well as how to gear up and what types of endgame PvE content exist.
Step 1. Finish MSQ, get AF Gear, and farm Tomestones for gear
Explanation of Terms, Loot, and Lockouts Lockout Reset All weekly lockouts are reset at Tuesday, 1AM PST/4 AM EST/8AM GMT.</description></item><item><title>Zyrk's Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing</title><link>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guides.xivresources.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</guid><description>Zyrk’s FFXIV Shadowbringers Healing Guide Learn how to hate your party, the game, and yourself About the Author Hi, I’m Zyrkhan Dar’locke. My name is blue on The Balance, and that’s basically all I have to say for myself. You may also know me as “what?” and “literally who.” I’m here to talk about healing and stuff, because I guess I like it or something, mostly because I don’t respect myself.</description></item></channel></rss>